<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kubernetes on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</title><link>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/categories/kubernetes/</link><description>Recent content in Kubernetes on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Installer Addon for NetApp Trident using kubectl - Update</title><link>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2021/01/22/tridentautomatedinstall_update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 06:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2021/01/22/tridentautomatedinstall_update/</guid><description>Trident Installer Addon Three month ago I published my first version of an automated NetApp Trident installer for Kubernetes cluster. In the last days I had some time to continue development on my installer. Time to change: my first version based on a bash script which runs in extra docker container. For running the script it was required to mount the kubeconfig file into the docker container.
Now the architecture of the installer changed to a single manifest which includes all required parts.</description></item><item><title>Automated install of NetApp Trident using kubectl</title><link>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2020/09/10/tridentautomatedinstall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2020/09/10/tridentautomatedinstall/</guid><description>Who wasn‘t yet faced the challenge to install NetApp Trident on multiple kubernetes clusters? NetApp provides very good documentation on ReadTheDocs. But you must execute the instruction step by step.
In addition to this documentation, I would like to introduce a way to install trident automatically in any k8s cluster via kubectl.
The following yaml file can be used for this:
--- apiVersion: v1 kind: Pod metadata: name: k8s-trident-installer labels: app: trident-installer spec: containers: - name: installer image: fabianborn/k8s-trident-installer:latest ports: - containerPort: 19811 volumeMounts: - name: kconfig mountPath: &amp;#34;/config&amp;#34; subPath: kubeconfig env: - name: DEBUG value: &amp;#34;0&amp;#34; volumes: - name: kconfig configMap: name: trident-install-kubeconfig In preparation, the yaml file subPath: kubeconfig must be adapted to the original kubeconfig name.</description></item><item><title>Jenkins K8s NetApp CI/CD Demo - Part 2</title><link>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2019/04/03/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2019/04/03/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p2/</guid><description>The last article shows, how you should prepare your environment. This post describes the configuration of GitLab and Jenkins.
Jenkins configuration At first Jenkins has to be configured. This will be done by WebUI, which is reachable by http://NODE_IP:8080/login
After a successfull authenication you will redirect to the Jenkins Dashboard. Configuring Credentials For the CI/CD demo with the WebApp requires some credentials:
for Docker Hub, for uploading the Docker image GitLab for reading the files or starting the WebHook Credential for Dockerhub On the left side go to &amp;ldquo;Credential&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Global credential (unrestricted)&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Add Credential&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Jenkins K8s NetApp CI/CD Demo - Part 1</title><link>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2019/03/21/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://hungry-carson-5114f7.netlify.app/blog/2019/03/21/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p1/</guid><description>This example will show you the CI/CD integration with Jenkins, Kubernetes and NetApp on a simple Web Application.
Pre-requisits Before start this demo there are some requirements:
Docker Hub Account for publishing the docker image a GIT repository (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, etc.) Kubernetes Cluster NetApp Storage System (FAS/AFF/CVO) Trident must be configured in K8s cluster &amp;ndash; Link: Trident Docs helm charts must be configured in K8s cluster &amp;ndash; Link: Helm Chart Docs Preparation environment Cloning Git repository Goto my GitHub repository: github-repo</description></item></channel></rss>