<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jenkins on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/categories/jenkins/</link><description>Recent content in Jenkins on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 21:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://project.epicshit.io/categories/jenkins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jenkins K8s NetApp CI/CD Demo - Part 2</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2019/04/03/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2019/04/03/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p2/</guid><description>The last article shows, how you should prepare your environment. This post describes the configuration of GitLab and Jenkins.
Jenkins configuration At first Jenkins has to be configured. This will be done by WebUI, which is reachable by http://NODE_IP:8080/login
After a successfull authenication you will redirect to the Jenkins Dashboard. Configuring Credentials For the CI/CD demo with the WebApp requires some credentials:
for Docker Hub, for uploading the Docker image GitLab for reading the files or starting the WebHook Credential for Dockerhub On the left side go to &amp;ldquo;Credential&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;System&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Global credential (unrestricted)&amp;rdquo; -&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Add Credential&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Jenkins K8s NetApp CI/CD Demo - Part 1</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2019/03/21/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2019/03/21/jenkins-kubernetes-netapp-cicd-integration-p1/</guid><description>This example will show you the CI/CD integration with Jenkins, Kubernetes and NetApp on a simple Web Application.
Pre-requisits Before start this demo there are some requirements:
Docker Hub Account for publishing the docker image a GIT repository (Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, etc.) Kubernetes Cluster NetApp Storage System (FAS/AFF/CVO) Trident must be configured in K8s cluster &amp;ndash; Link: Trident Docs helm charts must be configured in K8s cluster &amp;ndash; Link: Helm Chart Docs Preparation environment Cloning Git repository Goto my GitHub repository: github-repo</description></item></channel></rss>