<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GCP on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/categories/gcp/</link><description>Recent content in GCP on -:: Cloud is yours and all the new things ::-</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://project.epicshit.io/categories/gcp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Add Kubernetes Cluster to Astra Control</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/04/03/buildyourenv-addbackup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/04/03/buildyourenv-addbackup/</guid><description>Automated enabling backup In the first post, we wrote about the requirements for an optimized DevOps environment. In the second, we provisioned the Kubernetes cluster with NetApp storage.
As soon as applications run in the Kubernetes cluster and generate data, there is no getting around the topic of backup. Astra Control is used as the backup solution.
Astra Control is NetApp&amp;rsquo;s solution for Application-Aware Backup of Kubernetes apps. Astra Control backs up application metadata in addition to PVCs.</description></item><item><title>Build your DevOps Environment!</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/03/21/buildyourenv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/03/21/buildyourenv/</guid><description>Build your DevOps Environment! The LinkedIn post &amp;ldquo;NetApp in a Cloud DevOps Context&amp;rdquo; showed how an optimized Kubernetes environment can look in the cloud. This series of articles now show how to build such an environment in an automated way.
There will be four parts to this series.
Part 1: Planning Part 2: Setting up the required infrastructure Part 3: Activation of the backup Part 4: Monitoring and optimization of the environment The cloud providers Microsoft Azure and Google Cloud Platform are used to set up the test environments.</description></item><item><title>NetApp in a Cloud DevOps Context!</title><link>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/02/08/netappclouddevopscontext/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://project.epicshit.io/blog/2022/02/08/netappclouddevopscontext/</guid><description>﻿NetApp in a Cloud DevOps Context! Are you running a Kubernetes platform in the cloud based on cloud provider native services today? Then let me show you how NetApp can help to optimize this environment.
Each cloud provider uses its own storage products for its Kubernetes services, which are addressed via the CSI driver. In a NetApp optimized world, the &amp;ldquo;standard&amp;rdquo; driver will be replaced by Astra Trident. With Trident, it is now possible to use PVC on a cloud-optimized ONTAP: Cloud Volume Service, Azure NetApp Files, Cloud Volume ONTAP or FSx for NetApp ONTAP are the perfect solutions.</description></item></channel></rss>